GARRARD KITCHEN, B.Sc (Hons)

+44 (0)1704 233 521 +44 (0)7795 575 000 garrardkitchen@gmail.com www.garrardkitchen.com Skype: garrard.kitchen LinkedIn: garrard-kitchen

1 Beresford Drive Churchtown Southport PR9 7JY

Interests include:

- Serverless technology
- DevOps
- AWS
- Azure
- Machine Learning
- Security
- Research
- Project Management
- Product Owner

Ideal locations:

- Southport
- Liverpool
- Manchester
- Preston

Full driving license

Profile

I am a technical project leader, experienced in communicating at all levels, with commercial awareness, I am accustomed to identifying improvement opportunities outside of scope.

At my last position, CTO/Developer, I had developed and nurtured a culture of DevOps. This gave me and my team the freedom, responsibility and ownership necessary to help drive the business. With the use of appropriate services (CloudWatch, Datadog, OpsGenie, Sentry.io, Epsagon, Stackify, Slack) to deliver observability, and frameworks, I instilled the AWS Operational Excellence & Reliability pillars into the company's culture. This included, but was not limited too, the creation of runbooks across multiple platforms to automate (e.g. autoscale ECS Fargate containers) and monitor both infrastructure and solution features to minimise downtime (RPO). I architected massively scalable HA, faulttolerant and secure solutions, with DR, driven by serverless technology (such as AWS Lambda, Step Functions, API Gateway & ECS Fargate) and loosely coupled (e.g. Amazon SQS, SNS & Kinesis Data Streams). I used .NET Core (C# & F#), python and node.js interchangeably during my time in this position. My architecture included several different types of database (RDBMS, NoSQL & in-memory) including Aurora, MS SQL, DynamoDB, ElasticSearch & Redis). All my systems were integrated, packaged and deployed using a common CI/CD approach using tools such as Azure DevOps, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, OctopusDeploy, BitBucket Pipelines and Jenkins. My chosen container orchestration solution was ECS Fargate with ECR and Docker Hub registries. All stages of the release cycle were both monitored and automated. I created a polyglot development environment with a team that gave maximum effort and commitment. My serverless journey started on the Azure platform several years ago. I have used Azure for several years and using this platform I have architected, developed and deployed several massively scalable solutions.

I have a proven track record of systems integrations, acting as a remote worker manager of a European team, project managing across multiple time zones and cultures. I have a strong technical background in both server & client side development as well as serverless technologies (infrastructure, services & frameworks) and solutions delivery driven by DevOps. I am obsessive about quality UX, and with solutions that deliver on a positive CX. I am a full-stack developer.

Experience

CTO, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Sep 2008—Present
I managed a team of remote workers around Europe to develop single server,
HA & cloud based solutions using a range of technologies.

I lead technical projects, architecting product systems and feature solutions and coordinating integrations with partner/SI teams around the globe.

The role is varied; ranging from technical presentations to CxO, DevOps, Full-Stack development to root cause analysis. I categorise myself as a CTO/developer with extensive serverless development experience specialising in DevOps. Reporting directly to the CEO.

Contractor, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Jan 2007—Sep 2008
I was employed originally to develop an API for a company's client/server product. This involved employing Unit testing techniques such as TDD and documentation software and then to ship to integration partners.
I was also awarded the project to design and develop an e-learning and coaching web platform, hosted on self-managed Rackspace servers.
The work gave me my first experience of AWS services.
I worked with partners & system integrators around the world. I was asked to work full-time.

Contractor, Co-Op; Bromsgrove — 2005—Jan 2006
I was commissioned to support and enhance solutions using ASP, ASP.NET, c#, javascript, HTML and CSS. This role also included supporting Cadbury's with the Holos product (EIS). I was asked to work full-time.

Client-side web developer Team Lead, AIM Technology — Apr 2003—2004

I headed up the client-side development effort of a Scorecard web-application.

This was eventually bought by Aspect.

Data Architect, AIM Technology - Nov 2002-Aug 2003

My primary role was to consolidate data from disparate systems into a Scorecard application. My responsibilities included providing an OLAP solution, BI, data analytics, pre-sales support, product installation, support and diagnostics. I worked both onsite and offsite. Other duties included enhancing the corporate website.

Education

John Moores University, Liverpool — Business Information Systems Degree (Hons), 1994

North East Wales Institute, Connah's Quay - National Diploma in Computer Science, 1990

Certification

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate Certification, 2018-2021 AWS Developer - Associate Certification, 2017-2020 1st Dan, Black belt, 2010

Skills

Technical project leadership, remote team management, technical presentations and documentation, experienced in communication at all levels, meeting facilitator, educator, coach, agile development, root cause analysis and problem solving, microservices, AWS certified, Azure, full-stack developer, serverless development, CI/CD, system integration, RDBMS (MSSQL, MySQL, Aurora), NoSQL, ElasticSearch, Big Data, containers (ECS Fargate, Linux, Windows), CloudFormation (configuration as code), git, C#, F#, javascript, ES6, .NET Core, .NET Framework, ASP.NET Core Razor Pages, RESTful APIs, AWS Glue, WCF, SOA, WS-*, RIA, Silverlight, XAML, Sockets, Python, Node.js, Go, ETL, Microsoft, Linux, Authentication, UX, Bootstrap, JQuery, Angular, React, Vue

References

Costas Johnson - CEO Qualtrak Solutions, +44 (0)777 5520 459, costas.johnson@qualtrak.com - http://www.garrardkitchen.com/reference.pdf

Hobbies

Cycling, reading, research, cooking, walking, drone flying, golf and Ju-Jitsu